Guide to the Debbie Daum Gersh Family papers, 1937-2012 MS 850
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Daum/Gersh Family papers
1937-2012
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Gersh, Debbie Daum
MS 850
1 Linear Feet (1 box)
The collection consists of a binder of the Houston Hadassah chapter's Business and Professional committee's meeting minutes and other Hadassah materials, yearbooks, directories, recipes and newspaper clippings ranging from 1937 to 2012.
Biographical / Historical
Dora Ginsberg was born March 25, 1901, in Russia to Ben and Minnie (Asch) Ginsberg. Her father immigrated to the United States in 1901, and the rest of the family followed in 1903. Dora and her four siblings grew up in San Antonio. Samuel S. Daum was born in Austin March 6, 1898, to Joseph and Annie Daum. Sam and Dora were married in 1923, and the couple had one child, Arthur, born September 17, 1930, in Houston. Sam made his living as a bookkeeper for different types of businesses over the years, including dry goods, candy, and furniture. Dora was very active with the Houston area Hadassah chapter among other organizations. She was diagnosed with Muscular Sclerosis around 1949, and died August 4, 1956. Sam died June 21, 1961. Both are buried at Beth Yeshurun Cemetery in Houston.
Marian Edith Peterman was born in Galveston December 16, 1930, to Irving and Leah (Zinn) Peterman. Arthur Daum married Marian in 1953, and the couple had three children, including Deborah "Debbie" Cay Daum. Marian attended the University of Texas at Austin, where she was actively involved with the Texas Hillel. She was very active within the Houston Jewish community and received many awards and distinctions from Camp Young Judaea and Hadassah.
Debbie Daum was born in Houston, April 1957. She graduated from Bellaire High School in 1975 and married David Gersh in 1995.
Scope and Contents
Recorded minutes from the Houston Hadassah chapter's Business and Professional committee meetings from 1937 to 1945, a summary of a session at the 26th Annual Convention in 1940, and a newspaper clipping document some of the actions and events undertaken by the Houston Hadassah chapter between 1937 and 1952. Also included are University of Houston yearbooks, San Jacinto High School alumni directories and a graduating class photo, recipes, and a financial document from Houston Hillel. Of particular interest are meeting minutes that record every monthly meeting the chapter's Business and Professional committee held from January of 1937 to May of 1944 and a few meetings in 1945.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The material was donated by Debbie Daum Gersh in March 2019.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in one series as follows:
Series I: General
Related Materials
MS 775, Houston Hadassah collection
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life
Document Types
Minutes (Records); Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); yearbooks; directories
Subjects (Persons)
Gersh, Debbie Daum
- Series I: General, 1937-2012
  - Binder of Hadassah meeting minutes, 1937-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Summary of B&P Session of twenty-sixth annual convention, 1940-11-03 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - University of Houston yearbook - The Houstonian, 1949 (Box 1)
  - University of Houston yearbook - The Houstonian, 1950 (Box 1)
  - University of Houston yearbook - The Houstonian, 1951 (Box 1)
  - University of Houston yearbook - The Houstonian, 1952 (Box 1)
  - News clipping, "Hadassah to Honor National Visitor at Tea Party", 1952-05-08 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - San Jacinto High School graduating class photograph, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Longfellow metal tag, 1964 (Box 1, Envelope 5)
  - Correspondence with Harris County DA John Holmes regrarding anti-semitic remarks made by prosecutor Kelly Siegler, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - San Jacinto High School Alumni Directory, 2007 (Box 1)
  - San Jacinto High School Alumni Directory, 2012 (Box 1)
  - Recipes, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Houston Hillel building repair estimate, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)